# ALEXANDER BULDAKOV

Glazov, Russia • hamrammi@gmail.com



# Software developer

## Summary

Highly experienced in modern Web technologies. My professional journey began in 2012 when I learned PHP, HTML and CSS. A bit later I was introduced to the mighty world of JavaScript. Since then, JavaScript has been my favourite language.

At the moment I have 10+ years of programming experience. I can do a lot of complex tasks such as architecture design, choosing a better software stack, solving problems and, of course, write better code.

I worked a lot as a Fullstack web developer with the main focus on Frontend engineering.

I prefer to work remotely. My English is fluent.

## Work Experience

2018 - 2018

#### Team Lead

#### Monoreto

- Created whole application from scratch
- · Architecture design
- Lead programmer
- Consulting
- Code-review

2012-09 - current

#### Fullstack Developer

#### NewIT Ltd

- Started new projects. Helped with architecture design and choosing a right software stack.
- Implemented new features. Solved problems.
- Helped new teammates to start coding.
- Ensured implementation of best SEO practices.
- Improved our inner system workflow
- Implemented durable, persistent and fast synchronization mechanism between our servers

2023 - current

## Frontend/Fullstack Developer

Moscow-based personal development startup (Prednaznachenie)

- Architecture design
- Coding
- UI/UX (This is card-based application, you can drag-n-drop cards, reorder them, save progress, set goals, outline needed steps etc)
- Some backend work (since I was the only developer)

2015 - current

#### Developer

Occasional part-time hires

- Frontend
- Backend
- Architecture design
- Dealing with legacy code...

Education

2007 - 2012

Master Degree in Computer Science Glazov State Pedagogical Institute

### Portfolio

School Catering System — huge SaaS project. Fully implemented from scratch inside NewlT Ltd. walls. Fully transparent school dinner transaction history available anywhere so parents can be sure that their children are fed and healthy. I'm responsible for implementing parents' dashboard (frontend: React, Typescript, Next.js, Redux Toolkit) and synchronization between servers (scripting: Python, RabbitMQ)

Dispatching system — SaaS project. We gather and aggregate water meter readings. Anyone can see how many water their use and whether water meters are in good condition. I'm responsible for implementing end users' dashboard (frontend: React, Typescript, Redux, Chart.js) and administrators' dashboard (backend: PHP, Yii2)

NewIT Ltd: huge amount of inner corporate projects where I mostly refactored, implemented new features, solved bugs and did other routine tasks.

Monoreto — An Instagram like e-commerce project with some unique features. Architecture design, coding (Vue, Vuex), consulting, leading a team, that were my tasks. At the very beginning I did a bit of backend job but later fully switched to frontend.

Skills —					
Javascript/Typescript	Python, Java  Django, Twisted. Did some Java work a while ago  PHP				
Typescript, React, Redux, ReduxToolkit, RTK Query, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js and a lot more					
Node.js					
Express, Socket.io etc.	Laravel, Yii2, Codelgniter				
Databases	Tools				
MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB	Git, Webpack, NPM, NVM, Yarn, Memcache, Redis, RabbitMQ, Firebase and a huge amount of modern technologies.				
HTML/CSS	DevOps				
Tailwind (beloved), Styled Components, Twitter Bootstrap, Sass, whatever else	Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), bash scripting, Docker, Vagrant, Apache, Nginx, MySQL and many others.				

Created with **TVisualCV** 

